# **Mark Towey**

# 44 Castlelawn Heights, Galway marktowey1@gmail.com / 087 2559769

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

A confident and ambitious individual with experience as a Cloud Support Engineer and many years' experience as a primary school teacher. Although teaching provided me with great work experience and many transferable skills, I was eager to take on a new challenge in the business world. After completing a Master's in Business Analytics at University of Galway where I received a Student Ambassador Scholarship and achieved a 1.1 overall result, I commenced working with SAP SuccessFactors as a Cloud Support Engineer. This has given me a fresh drive and purpose in my working life and I am keen to progress in this field. With strong communication, interpersonal and problem-solving skills along with an ability to react to challenging situations, show composure in tense, high stress level situations and a desire to help others, I am sure that I can be a valued member of your team.

### **EDUCATION**

2020 – 2021	Master's in Business Analytics, H1 – NUI Galway
2019 – 2020	Higher Diploma in Business Studies, H1 - NUI Galway
2009 – 2012	Bachelor of Education, H2.2 – St. Patricks College, Drumcondra

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

April 2024 - Present

Software Implementation Consultant – Genesys, Galway

#### Jun 2021 - March 2024

# Cloud Support Engineer – SAP Successfactors, Galway

- Analysing incidents, researching solutions and providing clear communication and answers to customers.
- Liaising with Product Management and Software Development Teams to identify bugs and missing product functionality for future releases.
- Perform Root Cause Analysis and provide solutions in complex environment fields and areas.
- Collaborate with fellow employees across different teams by providing important customer feedback, process-improvement suggestions, new troubleshooting tips and other actions that involve improving our product.
- Working remotely and independently to achieve my goals and provide customers with a positive experience.

# Aug 2018 – July 2019 Primary School Teacher – Emirates International School, Dubai.

- Articulate complex theories using simple verbiage to a diverse audience.
- Taught in an international, private school in Dubai.
- Attended weekly meetings with the year 5 team and the vice principal to reflect, collaborate and proactively plan for future lessons and activities.
- Taught and built strong relationships with students, teachers and staff of different nationalities, cultures and backgrounds.

# Sept 2012 – June 2018 Primary School Teacher

Taught children of varying abilities, backgrounds, and learning difficulties.

- Plan, organise and implement lessons, activities, excursions daily.
- Lead, encourage, motivate, and inspire students to fulfil their potential.

### **OTHER WORK HISTORY**

• **Presiding Officer** Local Elections, 2014 – present.

• Travel Lived and worked in Canada & California, 2016 - 2017

Tennis Coach Castlebar Tennis Club, 2009 – 2018
Sales Assistant Toymaster, Castlebar, 2009- 2012

#### **SKILLS**

# Technical skills

- Java Currently learning Java on codecademy.com
- o AWS Completed a AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials course on Amazon.com
- Python Possess a working knowledge of how to prepare datasets, present data visualisations and support-decision making using Python.
- o **C#** Competent in object-oriented programming for the business environment.
- SQL Familiar with RDBMS database concepts. Can create relational database schema, guery database systems and manipulate data in a relational database.
- SAP SuccessFactors Employee Central expert.
- Tableau Competent at creating data visualisations to identify key findings.
- Big Data Tools Experience using tools such as Hadoop, MapReduce, Yarn, Spark, HDFS, HBase, Hive and Pig.
- **Communication skills** Possess excellent communication skills as it is essential to provide clear, concise explanations to customers.
- **Customer Service Skills** Enjoy providing a positive experience for customers. Have an overall customer satisfaction score much greater than the SAP company average.
- **Teamwork skills** Played GAA and soccer for many years and have a great understanding of the importance of teamwork and collaboration.
- Leadership skills Demonstrated strong leadership skills daily while teaching. I developed these skills further while working as a presiding officer at local elections and while running children's tennis camps.

# **INTEREST/HOBBIES**

- **Gaelic Football** Current player with Castlebar Mitchells. Competed in the 2016 All-Ireland club final. Represented Mayo at underage level.
- Soccer Played with Castlebar Celtic and represented Mayo at underage level.
- Tennis I am a Tennis Ireland certified coach. Represented Connaught at junior level.
- Volunteer Work Spent two weeks in Zambia with Zamda Ireland in 2018.
- Travel Travelled in Europe, N America, Middle East, South-East Asia & China.

## References available on request